First he changed music, then he changed the world.
Bob Marley: One Love is a music, history, drama film
directed by Reinaldo Marcus Green.
Jamaican singer-songwriter Bob Marley overcomes adversity to
become the most famous reggae musician in the world.
Bob Marley, played by Kingsley Ben-Adir.
Rita Marley, played by Lashana Lynch.
Chris Blackwell, played by James Norton.
Tyrone Downie, played by Tosin Cole.
Cindy Breakspeare, played by Umi Myers.
Don Taylor, played by Anthony Welsh.
Bob Marley: One Love is a 2024 American biographical musical drama film based on the life of reggae singer and
songwriter Bob Marley, played by Kingsley Ben-Adir, from his rise to fame in the mid-1970s to his death in 1981.
The film is directed by Reinaldo Marcus Green, who co-wrote
the screenplay with Terence Winter, Frank E.
Flowers, and Zach Baylin.
It also stars Lashana Lynch as Rita Marley and James Norton as Chris Blackwell.
Bob Marley: One Love premiered at the Carib 5 in Kingston, Jamaica, on January 23, 2024, and
was released in the United States by Paramount Pictures on February 14, 2024.
It received mixed reviews from critics and grossed $180 million worldwide.
The film explores themes of london, england, jamaica,
biography, rastafarian, reggae music.
The tone is emotional.